Guide to the Harriet Doerr Papers, 1976-1996
Department of Special Collections
- Adenda, materials received 4/30/96, Accession 96-068
  - Series I: The Tiger in the Grass (published 1995)
    - "Consider This, Señora" (later "Sun, Pure Air, and a View"): final draft (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Sleeve of Rain" (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Edie: A Life": class comments (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - "Edie: A Life", comments by L'Heureux (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "Edie: A Life", original poem and more drafts (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - The Tiger in the Grass: Table of Contents and Dedication pages (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, first TMS with corrections (Parts I & II) (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, first TMS with corrections (Part III) (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, first TMS with corrections (Parts IV & V) (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - The Tiger in the Grass: early Mss (Parts II & III) (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - The Tiger in the Grass: early Mss (Parts IV & V) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, original Viking Mss (Parts II & III) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, original Viking Mss (Parts IV & V) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, Viking Mss with corrections, 5/19/95,(p.i-89) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, Viking Mss with corrections, 5/19/95(p.90-167) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, Copy Editing pages with corrections, 6/15/95,(p.i-89) (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, Copy Editing pages with corrections, 6/15/95,(p.90-167) (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - The Tiger in the Grass: rough pages/galley proofs, 7/25/95,(p.i-88) (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, rough pages/galley proofs, 7/25/95(p.89-206) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, Rough pages/galley proofs corrections (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, page proofs, 8/31/95,(p.i-90) (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - The Tiger in the Grass: page proofs, 8/31/95,(p.91-209) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - The Tiger in the Grass, Viking edition (book) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Series II: Consider This, Señora
    - "Picnic at Amapolas": original and notes (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Easter Weekend" (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "Goya and the Widow Bowles" (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "A Over Middle C" (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "Truckloads of Tuberoses" (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "Another Short Day in La Luz" (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "Bud on the Side of the Angels" (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - "Exit the Widow" (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - "The Bandstand in the Square" (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - "The Bandstand in the Square", larger font-size copies (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - "As It Happened" (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Consider This, Señora: copy editing corrections (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Consider This, Señora, promotions (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Consider This, Señora, reviews (6/93-8/22/93) (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Consider This, Señora, reviews (8/27/93-12/94)& no date (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Consider This, Señora: best seller lists (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Series III: Stones for Ibarra
    - Stones for Ibarra: title pages (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Stones for Ibarra, last chapter ("To Know Its Ways") (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Series IV: Miscellaneous Short Stories
    - "400 Block, 3:30pm" (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "Alta Mira" (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - "The Baptists" (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - "A Clear Understanding" (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - "Dear Dr.Hadley" (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "Handling Time" (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - "Houses" (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - "Landmarks: Ibarra - Pages from a Notebook" (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - "Letters from Mexico" (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - "Loreto" (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - "Lunch with the Bishop" (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - "One Day at a Time" (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - "My Aunt Alexa": class comments (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - "The Rearrangement" (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - "Reincarnations" (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - "Santa Felicia" (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Series V: Readings, Signings, and Promotionals
    - Reading at "The Y," 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - National Kidney Foundation Authors' Luncheon, 5/94 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Harvest, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Tucson book signings, 11/95 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Series VI: Professional Correspondence
    - The Atlantic: Michael Curtis, 1986-1991 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Darhansoff & Verrill Publishing, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Doubleday Publishing, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Epoch, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Harleman, Anne, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - The Huntington: Robert Middlekauf, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - The Los Angeles Times, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Sayre, Constance (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - The Sequoia, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - W.W. Norton Publishing: Janet Sternberg, 1987-1993 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - The Writer, 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Yolla Bolly Publishers: Under an Aztec Sun, 1988-1992 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Series VII: General Correspondence (mostly fan letters), 1988-1996
    - Correspondence: 1988-1992 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1992envelopes (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1/93-8/93 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1/93-8/93envelopes (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 9/93 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 9/93envelopes (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 10/93-12/93 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 10/93-12/93envelopes (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1/94-4/94 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1/94-4/94envelopes (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 5/94-12/94 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 5/94-12/94envelopes (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996envelopes (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, no date (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Photos removed from letters (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Series VIII: Computer Disks
    - Computer disks (probably containing drafts of stories) (Box 25, Folder 7)
Separated Material
Oversized pamphlet for Yolla Bolly (unrelated to Doerr) removed to M0518